DAVID EZZIDDINE

Contact

13332 SE 122nd Ave, #C-10 Clackamas, OR 97015

tel 505-699-7412 email dezziddine@gmail.com

Education

West Texas A&M University
Canyon, TX — BFA in Painting, 1998

Additional Education

University of North Texas

Denton, TX — Sculpture, 1998-1999

St. Joost Art Academy Breda, The Netherlands, 1990-1991

Skills

- Extensive people and creative problem solving skills
- Ability to follow written and verbal directions and work independently
- Proficient in Mac and PC platforms
- Skilled in Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, Dreamweaver, Gallery Pro, MS Word, Excel and Outlook programs
- Ability to design in and write HTML and CSS programing languages
- Adept with various power tools and display construction techniques
- Well-versed in the exhibition and lighting of two and three-dimensional artworks

References

Henry Monahan, Director Morning Star Gallery 505-982-8187 / indian@morningstargallery.com

Nedra Matteucci, Owner Nedra Matteucci Galleries, Inc 505-982-4631 / inquiry@matteucci.com

Roberta Brashears, Operations Manager Nedra Matteucci Galleries, Inc. Former Director - Nedra Matteucci Fine Art 505-982-4631 / roberta@matteucci.com

Amel Esposito, Law Offices of Amel Esposito Former Executive Vice President -American Claims Management 619-313-4212 / aesposito@coronadoclaims.com

Profile

I am a driven, hardworking and creative individual who possesses a multi-faceted skill set. My experiences have given me the opportunity to acquire knowledge in many areas ranging from general design and aesthetics to the efficient use of technology and on to the specialized nature of Native American pottery and textiles. I learn quickly and am able to make reasoned, rational decisions based on previous experience and the goals of the task at hand.

Experience

Nedra Matteucci Galleries, Inc

Operations Manager, Morning Star Gallery Santa Fe, NM 01/2011-02/2013

As the Operations Manager, my primary responsibility was handling the day to day business of the gallery including maintenance of the inventory and client database, daily financials, and sales. During the gallery's thirty year history, many of it's daily protocols had become outdated and failed to fully utilize the available technology. I successfully implemented a number of new procedures which maintained data integrity, improved efficiency and reduced paper waste. I also re-designed, re-created and maintained the gallery website. I created a modern, yet timeless design that emphasized the beauty of the object and improved the end user experience. Furthermore, I was actively involved in the development and design of advertising materials and show invitations.

Nedra Matteucci Galleries, Inc

Assistant Director, Nedra Matteucci Fine Art Santa Fe, NM 07/2010-01/2011

As Assistant Director, I worked closely with the Director to produce multiple exhibitions for national and international artists. I maintained working relationships and contracts with up to twenty gallery artists and an extensive client list. I prepared daily and monthly financial reports for the accounting department. Additionally, I was involved in the design of advertising materials and upkeep of the gallery website. I transferred to Morning Star Gallery when Nedra Matteucci Fine Art was consolidated into the main Matteucci Gallery.

Constellation Home Electronics

Warehouse Manager Santa Fe, NM 06/2009-07/2010

I managed the inventory of high end home theater and electronics store as well as parts and supplies for the installation department. I assisted with setting up the point of sale system in the new retail store, including programming barcodes and developing ordering protocols.

Altermann Galleries & Auctioneers

Registrar / Auction Coordinator Santa Fe, NM 03/2008-06/2009

I performed multiple duties as both the gallery Registrar and the Auction Coordinator. My Registrar duties included maintenance of the gallery database and preparation of consignment contracts. Further, I supervised one Assistant Registrar in charge of inventory control and shipping. As Auction Coordinator, I was responsible for all aspects of the production of five auctions of historical western art; including set up of the preview gallery, coordination with the online and telephone bidding services and shipping of sold works. I was also responsible for the creation of all advertising materials and produced the catalogs for each auction.

Nedra Matteucci Galleries, Inc

Gallery Associate, Nedra Matteucci Fine Art Santa Fe, NM 09/2007-03/2008

In my role as a Gallery Associate, I focused on sales and developed relationships with new and existing clients. In addition, I assisted with the hanging of exhibitions and maintenance of the gallery.

American Claims Management

Litigated Claims Specialist San Diego, CA 06/2003-07/2007

As a Claims Specialist, I managed a daily average of 120 litigated automotive and property claims. My duties involved researching the circumstances of disputed claims, evaluating medical treatments and attempting settlement prior to extensive litigation. I also directed the actions of hired defense counsel on claims which proceeded to arbitration or trial.